"quote_1" to "Agriculture is the most healthful, most useful and most noble employment of man. - George Washington",
"quote_2" to "The farmer is the only man in our economy who buys everything at retail, sells everything at wholesale, and pays the freight both ways. - John F. Kennedy",
"quote_3" to "Farming is a profession of hope. - Brian Brett",
"quote_4" to "The ultimate goal of farming is not the growing of crops, but the cultivation and perfection of human beings. - Masanobu Fukuoka",
"quote_5" to "Hard work spotlights the character of people: some turn up their sleeves, some turn up their noses, and some don't turn up at all. - Sam Ewing",
"quote_6" to "Persistence is to the character of man as carbon is to steel. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_7" to "Success is not final, failure is not fatal: it is the courage to continue that counts. - Winston Churchill",
"quote_8" to "The only place where success comes before work is in the dictionary. - Vidal Sassoon",
"quote_9" to "Don't judge each day by the harvest you reap but by the seeds that you plant. - Robert Louis Stevenson",
"quote_10" to "The best way to predict your future is to create it. - Abraham Lincoln",
"quote_11" to "Hard work beats talent when talent doesn't work hard. - Tim Notke",
"quote_12" to "Farming looks mighty easy when your plow is a pencil and you're a thousand miles from the corn field. - Dwight D. Eisenhower",
"quote_13" to "The master's eye fattens the pig. - Proverb",
"quote_14" to "Great things are done by a series of small things brought together. - Vincent Van Gogh",
"quote_15" to "The foundation of every state is the education of its youth. - Diogenes",
"quote_16" to "Life on a farm is a school of patience. You can't hurry the crops or make an ox in two days. - Henri Alain",
"quote_17" to "Farming is not just a job, it's a way of life. - Unknown",
"quote_18" to "The goal is not to be better than the other man, but your previous self. - Dalai Lama",
"quote_19" to "Sustainability is about the future of our children and grandchildren. - Unknown",
"quote_20" to "The first duty of a farmer is to leave the soil better than he found it. - Unknown",
"quote_21" to "Work hard in silence, let your success be your noise. - Frank Ocean",
"quote_22" to "Persistence can change failure into extraordinary achievement. - Matt Biondi",
"quote_23" to "A farmer's work is never done, but the rewards are eternal. - Unknown",
"quote_24" to "Every day is a new opportunity to grow. - Unknown",
"quote_25" to "Growth is never by mere chance; it is the result of forces working together. - James Cash Penney",
"quote_26" to "The simple life is its own reward. - Unknown",
"quote_27" to "Farmers are the backbone of the world. - Unknown",
"quote_28" to "A field is only as good as the man who tends it. - Unknown",
"quote_29" to "To a farmer, every seed is a promise. - Unknown",
"quote_30" to "Faith is the bird that feels the light when the dawn is still dark. - Rabindranath Tagore",
"quote_31" to "Success usually comes to those who are too busy to be looking for it. - Henry David Thoreau",
"quote_32" to "There are no shortcuts to any place worth going. - Beverly Sills",
"quote_33" to "Believe you can and you're halfway there. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_34" to "Your heart is like a garden. You can plant flowers or you can plant weeds. - Unknown",
"quote_35" to "The discovery of agriculture was the first big step toward a civilized life. - Arthur Keith",
"quote_36" to "Cultivators of the earth are the most valuable citizens. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_37" to "The farmer has to be an optimist or he wouldn't still be a farmer. - Will Rogers",
"quote_38" to "It is only the farmer who faithfully plants seeds in the Spring, who reaps a harvest in the Autumn. - B.C. Forbes",
"quote_39" to "No race can prosper till it learns that there is as much dignity in tilling a field as in writing a poem. - Booker T. Washington",
"quote_40" to "If you tickle the earth with a hoe she laughs with a harvest. - Douglas Jerrold",
"quote_41" to "Agriculture not only gives riches to a nation, but the only riches she can call her own. - Samuel Johnson",
"quote_42" to "The art of agriculture is the art of being a partner with God. - Unknown",
"quote_43" to "Being a farmer means you have a great deal of patience. - Unknown",
"quote_44" to "Everything that slows us down and forces patience, everything that sets us back into the slow cycles of nature, is a help. - May Sarton",
"quote_45" to "The farmer is a magician who produces money from the mud. - Amit Kalantri",
"quote_46" to "Soil is the hidden half of nature. - Unknown",
"quote_47" to "Plowing is the foundation of agriculture. - Unknown",
"quote_48" to "Nature does not hurry, yet everything is accomplished. - Lao Tzu",
"quote_49" to "One who has a land has a gold. - African Proverb",
"quote_50" to "Take care of the land and the land will take care of you. - Unknown",
"quote_51" to "Small-scale farmers are the heroes of our food system. - Unknown",
"quote_52" to "Persistence is the twin sister of excellence. One is a matter of quality; the other, a matter of time. - Marabel Morgan",
"quote_53" to "Hard work is the formula for success. - Unknown",
"quote_54" to "The sweat of the farmer is the rain for the crops. - Unknown",
"quote_55" to "The harder you work for something, the greater you'll feel when you achieve it. - Unknown",
"quote_56" to "Success is the sum of small efforts, repeated day in and day out. - Robert Collier",
"quote_57" to "Dream big, work hard, stay focused. - Unknown",
"quote_58" to "Challenges are what make life interesting and overcoming them is what makes life meaningful. - Joshua J. Marine",
"quote_59" to "Don't wait for opportunity. Create it. - Unknown",
"quote_60" to "The secret of getting ahead is getting started. - Mark Twain",
"quote_61" to "Quality is not an act, it is a habit. - Aristotle",
"quote_62" to "I find that the harder I work, the more luck I seem to have. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_63" to "Strength and growth come only through continuous effort and struggle. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_64" to "Courage is not having the strength to go on; it is going on when you don't have the strength. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_65" to "The road to success is always under construction. - Lily Tomlin",
"quote_66" to "Failure is the condiment that gives success its flavor. - Truman Capote",
"quote_67" to "Do not be embarrassed by your failures, learn from them and start again. - Richard Branson",
"quote_68" to "Hard times don't create heroes. It is during the hard times when the 'hero' within us is revealed. - Bob Riley",
"quote_69" to "Character is the ability to carry out a good resolution long after the excitement of the moment has passed. - Cavett Robert",
"quote_70" to "Your harvest will come if you do not give up. - Unknown"
"quote_1" to "L'agriculture est l'emploi de l'homme le plus sain, le plus utile et le plus noble. - George Washington",
"quote_2" to "L'agriculteur est le seul homme dans notre économie qui achète tout au détail, vend tout en gros et paie le fret dans les deux sens. - John F. Kennedy",
"quote_3" to "L'agriculture est une profession d'espoir. - Brian Brett",
"quote_4" to "Le but ultime de l'agriculture n'est pas la culture de céréales, mais la culture et la perfection des êtres humains. - Masanobu Fukuoka",
"quote_5" to "Le travail acharné met en lumière le caractère des gens : certains retroussent leurs manches, certains froncent les sourcils et d'autres ne se présentent pas du tout. - Sam Ewing",
"quote_6" to "La persévérance est au caractère de l'homme ce que le carbone est à l'acier. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_7" to "Le succès n'est pas final, l'échec n'est pas fatal : c'est le courage de continuer qui compte. - Winston Churchill",
"quote_8" to "Le seul endroit où le succès vient avant le travail est dans le dictionnaire. - Vidal Sassoon",
"quote_9" to "Ne jugez pas chaque jour à la récolte que vous faites, mais aux graines que vous plantez. - Robert Louis Stevenson",
"quote_10" to "La meilleure façon de prédire votre avenir est de le créer. - Abraham Lincoln",
"quote_11" to "Le travail acharné bat le talent quand le talent ne travaille pas dur. - Tim Notke",
"quote_12" to "L'agriculture a l'air très facile quand votre charrue est un crayon et que vous êtes à mille kilomètres du champ de maïs. - Dwight D. Eisenhower",
"quote_13" to "L'œil du maître engraisse le porc. - Proverbe",
"quote_14" to "Les grandes choses se font par une série de petites choses rassemblées. - Vincent Van Gogh",
"quote_15" to "Le fondement de chaque État est l'éducation de sa jeunesse. - Diogenes",
"quote_16" to "La vie à la ferme est une école de patience. On ne peut pas presser les récoltes ou faire un bœuf en deux jours. - Henri Alain",
"quote_17" to "L'agriculture n'est pas seulement un travail, c'est un mode de vie. - Inconnu",
"quote_18" to "Le but n'est pas d'être meilleur que l'autre, mais d'être meilleur que votre moi précédent. - Dalai Lama",
"quote_19" to "La durabilité concerne l'avenir de nos enfants et petits-enfants. - Inconnu",
"quote_20" to "Le premier devoir d'un agriculteur est de laisser le sol en meilleur état qu'il ne l'a trouvé. - Inconnu",
"quote_21" to "Travaillez dur en silence, laissez votre succès faire du bruit. - Frank Ocean",
"quote_22" to "La persévérance peut transformer l'échec en une réussite extraordinaire. - Matt Biondi",
"quote_23" to "Le travail d'un fermier n'est jamais terminé, mais les récompenses sont éternelles. - Inconnu",
"quote_24" to "Chaque jour est une nouvelle opportunité de grandir. - Inconnu",
"quote_25" to "La croissance n'est jamais le fruit du hasard ; elle est le résultat de forces travaillant ensemble. - James Cash Penney",
"quote_26" to "La vie simple est sa propre récompense. - Inconnu",
"quote_27" to "Les agriculteurs sont la colonne vertébrale du monde. - Inconnu",
"quote_28" to "Un champ n'est bon que si l'homme qui s'en occupe l'est aussi. - Inconnu",
"quote_29" to "Pour un agriculteur, chaque graine est une promesse. - Inconnu",
"quote_30" to "La foi est l'oiseau qui sent la lumière quand l'aube est encore sombre. - Rabindranath Tagore",
"quote_31" to "Le succès vient généralement à ceux qui sont trop occupés pour le chercher. - Henry David Thoreau",
"quote_32" to "Il n'y a pas de raccourcis vers les endroits qui valent la peine d'aller. - Beverly Sills",
"quote_33" to "Croyez que vous pouvez et vous êtes déjà à mi-chemin. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_34" to "Votre cœur est comme un jardin. Vous pouvez planter des fleurs ou des mauvaises herbes. - Inconnu",
"quote_35" to "La découverte de l'agriculture a été le premier grand pas vers une vie civilisée. - Arthur Keith",
"quote_36" to "Les cultivateurs de la terre sont les citoyens les plus précieux. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_37" to "Le fermier doit être optimiste, sinon il ne serait pas fermier. - Will Rogers",
"quote_38" to "Seul le fermier qui plante fidèlement des graines au printemps récolte à l'automne. - B.C. Forbes",
"quote_39" to "Aucune race ne peut prospérer tant qu'elle n'a pas appris qu'il y a autant de dignité à cultiver un champ qu'à écrire un poème. - Booker T. Washington",
"quote_40" to "Si vous chatouillez la terre avec une houe, elle rit avec une récolte. - Douglas Jerrold",
"quote_41" to "L'agriculture non seulement donne des richesses à une nation, mais les seules richesses qu'elle peut appeler siennes. - Samuel Johnson",
"quote_42" to "L'art de l'agriculture est l'art d'être partenaire de Dieu. - Inconnu",
"quote_43" to "Être agriculteur signifie avoir beaucoup de patience. - Inconnu",
"quote_44" to "Tout ce qui nous ralentit et force la patience, tout ce qui nous replonge dans les cycles lents de la nature, est une aide. - May Sarton",
"quote_45" to "Le fermier est un magicien qui produit de l'argent de la boue. - Amit Kalantri",
"quote_46" to "Le sol est la moitié cachée de la nature. - Inconnu",
"quote_47" to "Le labourage est le fondement de l'agriculture. - Inconnu",
"quote_48" to "La nature ne se presse pas, et pourtant tout est accompli. - Lao Tzu",
"quote_49" to "Celui qui a une terre a de l'or. - Proverbe africain",
"quote_50" to "Prenez soin de la terre et la terre prendra soin de vous. - Inconnu",
"quote_51" to "Les petits agriculteurs sont les héros de notre système alimentaire. - Inconnu",
"quote_52" to "La persévérance est la sœur jumelle de l'excellence. L'une est une question de qualité ; l'autre, de temps. - Marabel Morgan",
"quote_53" to "Le travail acharné est la formule du succès. - Inconnu",
"quote_54" to "La sueur du fermier est la pluie pour les cultures. - Inconnu",
"quote_55" to "Plus vous travaillez dur pour quelque chose, plus vous vous sentirez bien quand vous l'obtiendrez. - Inconnu",
"quote_56" to "Le succès est la somme de petits efforts, répétés jour après jour. - Robert Collier",
"quote_57" to "Rêvez grand, travaillez dur, restez concentré. - Inconnu",
"quote_58" to "Les défis sont ce qui rend la vie intéressante et les surmonter est ce qui lui donne un sens. - Joshua J. Marine",
"quote_59" to "N'attendez pas l'opportunité. Créez-la. - Inconnu",
"quote_60" to "Le secret pour avancer est de commencer. - Mark Twain",
"quote_61" to "La qualité n'est pas un acte, c'est une habitude. - Aristote",
"quote_62" to "Je trouve que plus je travaille dur, plus j'ai de la chance. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_63" to "La force et la croissance ne viennent que par des efforts et des luttes continus. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_64" to "Le courage n'est pas d'avoir la force de continuer ; c'est de continuer quand on n'a plus de force. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_65" to "La route du succès est toujours en construction. - Lily Tomlin",
"quote_66" to "L'échec est le condiment qui donne au succès sa saveur. - Truman Capote",
"quote_67" to "Ne soyez pas embarrassé par vos échecs, apprenez d'eux et recommencez. - Richard Branson",
"quote_68" to "Les temps difficiles ne créent pas de héros. C'est pendant les temps difficiles que le 'héros' en nous se révèle. - Bob Riley",
"quote_69" to "Le caractère est la capacité à mener à bien une bonne résolution longtemps après que l'excitation du moment soit passée. - Cavett Robert",
"quote_70" to "Votre récolte viendra si vous n'abandonnez pas. - Inconnu"
"quote_1" to "农业是人类最健康、最有用、最高尚的职业。 - 乔治·华盛顿",
"quote_2" to "农民是我们经济中唯一一个以零售价买入一切，以批发价卖出一切，并双向支付运费的人。 - 约翰·F·肯尼迪",
"quote_3" to "务农是一种希望的职业。 - 布莱恩·布雷特",
"quote_4" to "务农的最终目标不是作物的生长，而是人的培养和完善。 - 福冈正信",
"quote_5" to "艰苦的工作能凸显人的性格：有些人卷起袖子，有些人皱起鼻子，还有些人根本不出现。 - 萨姆·尤因",
"quote_6" to "坚持之于人的性格，犹碳之于钢。 - 拿破仑·希尔",
"quote_7" to "成功不是终点，失败也不是终结：重要的是继续前进的勇气。 - 温斯顿·丘吉尔",
"quote_8" to "成功唯一排在工作前面的地方是在字典里。 - 维达·沙宣",
"quote_9" to "不要以收获多少来评判每一天，而要以播种多少来评判。 - 罗伯特·路易斯·史蒂文森",
"quote_10" to "预测未来的最好方法是创造它。 - 亚伯拉罕·林肯",
"quote_11" to "当才华不努力时，努力胜过才华。 - 蒂姆·诺特克",
"quote_12" to "当你的犁是一支铅笔，而你离玉米地有一千英里远时，务农看起来非常容易。 - 德怀特·D·艾森豪威尔",
"quote_13" to "主人的眼睛能养肥猪。 - 谚语",
"quote_14" to "伟大的事业是由一系列汇聚在一起的小事完成的。 - 文森特·梵高",
"quote_15" to "每一个国家的根基都在于对其青年的教育。 - 第欧根尼",
"quote_16" to "农场生活是一所耐心的学校。你不能催促庄稼生长，也不能在两天内造出一头牛。 - 亨利·阿兰",
"quote_17" to "务农不只是一份工作，它是一种生活方式。 - 佚名",
"quote_18" to "目标不是要比别人更好，而是要比过去的自己更好。 - 达赖喇嘛",
"quote_19" to "可持续发展关乎我们子孙后代的未来。 - 佚名",
"quote_20" to "农民的首要职责是让土地比他发现时更好。 - 佚名",
"quote_21" to "在沉默中努力工作，让成功成为你的呐喊。 - 弗兰克·奥申",
"quote_22" to "坚持可以将失败转化为非凡的成就。 - 马特·比昂迪",
"quote_23" to "农民的工作永无止境，但回报是永恒的。 - 佚名",
"quote_24" to "每一天都是成长的崭新机会。 - 佚名",
"quote_25" to "增长绝非偶然；它是各方力量共同作用的结果。 - 詹姆斯·卡什·潘尼",
"quote_26" to "简单生活本身就是回报。 - 佚名",
"quote_27" to "农民是世界的脊梁。 - 佚名",
"quote_28" to "田地的好坏取决于照料它的人。 - 佚名",
"quote_29" to "对于农民来说，每一颗种子都是一个承诺。 - 佚名",
"quote_30" to "信念是那只在黎明尚未降临时便感受到光明的鸟。 - 泰戈尔",
"quote_31" to "成功通常降临在那些忙得没时间寻找它的人身上。 - 亨利·大卫·梭罗",
"quote_32" to "通往任何值得去的地方都没有捷径。 - 贝弗利·希尔斯",
"quote_33" to "相信你能做到，你就已经成功了一半。 - 西奥多·罗斯福",
"quote_34" to "你的心就像一个花园。你可以种花，也可以种杂草。 - 佚名",
"quote_35" to "农业的发现是迈向文明生活的第一大步。 - 亚瑟·基思",
"quote_36" to "大地的耕耘者是最有价值的公民。 - 托马斯·杰斐逊",
"quote_37" to "农民必须是一个乐观主义者，否则他不会继续当农民。 - 威尔·罗杰斯",
"quote_38" to "只有在春天忠实播种的农民，才能在秋天收获。 - B.C. 福布斯",
"quote_39" to "除非学会耕田和写诗同样尊严，否则任何种族都无法繁荣。 - 布克·T·华盛顿",
"quote_40" to "如果你用锄头逗弄大地，她就会以丰收作为欢笑。 - 道格拉斯·杰罗德",
"quote_41" to "农业不仅给国家带来财富，而且是唯一她可以称之为自己的财富。 - 塞缪尔·约翰逊",
"quote_42" to "农业艺术是与上帝合作的艺术。 - 佚名",
"quote_43" to "当一名农民意味着你非常有耐心。 - 佚名",
"quote_44" to "任何让我们慢下来、迫使我们保持耐心的事情，任何让我们回到大自然缓慢循环的事情，都是一种帮助。 - 梅·萨顿",
"quote_45" to "农民是一位能从泥土中变出钱来的魔术师。 - 阿米特·卡兰特里",
"quote_46" to "土壤是大自然隐藏的一半。 - 佚名",
"quote_47" to "耕耘是农业的基础。 - 佚名",
"quote_48" to "自然从不匆忙，却无事不成。 - 老子",
"quote_49" to "拥有土地的人就拥有黄金。 - 非洲谚语",
"quote_50" to "照顾好土地，土地就会照顾你。 - 佚名",
"quote_51" to "小规模农民是我们粮食系统的英雄。 - 佚名",
"quote_52" to "坚持是卓越的孪生姐妹。一个是质量问题；另一个是时间问题。 - 玛拉贝尔·摩根",
"quote_53" to "努力工作是成功的公式。 - 佚名",
"quote_54" to "农民的汗水是作物的雨露。 - 佚名",
"quote_55" to "你为某事付出的努力越多，当你实现它时你的感觉就越棒。 - 佚名",
"quote_56" to "成功是日复一日积累的小努力的总和。 - 罗伯特·科利尔",
"quote_57" to "怀揣梦想，努力工作，保持专注。 - 佚名",
"quote_58" to "挑战让生活变得有趣，而克服挑战让生活变得有意义。 - 约书亚·J·马林",
"quote_59" to "不要等待机会。去创造它。 - 佚名",
"quote_60" to "领先的秘诀在于开始。 - 马克·吐温",
"quote_61" to "质量不是一种行为，而是一种习惯。 - 亚里士多德",
"quote_62" to "我发现我工作越努力，我的运气似乎就越好。 - 托马斯·杰斐逊",
"quote_63" to "力量和增长只能通过不断的努力和奋斗获得。 - 拿破仑·希尔",
"quote_64" to "勇气不是拥有继续前进的力量；而是在没有力量时依然继续前进。 - 西奥多·罗斯福",
"quote_65" to "通往成功的道路永远在建设中。 - 莉莉·汤姆林",
"quote_66" to "失败是给成功增添风味的调味品。 - 杜鲁门·卡波特",
"quote_67" to "不要为你的失败感到尴尬，从中学习并重新开始。 - 理查德·布兰森",
"quote_68" to "艰难时期不会创造英雄。正是在艰难时期，我们内在的‘英雄’才得以显现。 - 鲍勃·莱利",
"quote_69" to "性格是在那一刻的兴奋过去很久之后，依然能履行良好决议的能力。 - 卡维特·罗伯特",
"quote_70" to "如果你不放弃，你的收获终将到来。 - 佚名"
"quote_1" to "La agricultura es el empleo del hombre más saludable, más útil y más noble. - George Washington",
"quote_2" to "El agricultor es el único hombre en nuestra economía que compra todo al por menor, vende todo al por mayor y paga el flete en ambos sentidos. - John F. Kennedy",
"quote_3" to "La agricultura es una profesión de esperanza. - Brian Brett",
"quote_4" to "El objetivo final de la agricultura no es el cultivo de cosechas, sino el cultivo y la perfección de los seres humanos. - Masanobu Fukuoka",
"quote_5" to "El trabajo duro pone de relieve el carácter de las personas: algunos se arremangan, algunos arrugan la nariz y otros no aparecen en absoluto. - Sam Ewing",
"quote_6" to "La persistencia es para el carácter del hombre lo que el carbono es para el acero. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_7" to "El éxito no es el final, el fracaso no es fatal: es el valor para continuar lo que cuenta. - Winston Churchill",
"quote_8" to "El único lugar donde el éxito viene antes que el trabajo es en el diccionario. - Vidal Sassoon",
"quote_9" to "No juzgues cada día por la cosecha que recoges, sino por las semillas que plantas. - Robert Louis Stevenson",
"quote_10" to "La mejor manera de predecir tu futuro es creándolo. - Abraham Lincoln",
"quote_11" to "El trabajo duro vence al talento cuando el talento no trabaja duro. - Tim Notke",
"quote_12" to "La agricultura parece muy fácil cuando tu arado es un lápiz y estás a mil millas del campo de maíz. - Dwight D. Eisenhower",
"quote_13" to "El ojo del amo engorda al cerdo. - Proverbio",
"quote_14" to "Las cosas grandes se hacen mediante una serie de cosas pequeñas reunidas. - Vincent Van Gogh",
"quote_15" to "La base de todo estado es la educación de su juventud. - Diógenes",
"quote_16" to "La vida en una granja es una escuela de paciencia. No puedes apresurar las cosechas ni hacer un buey en dos días. - Henri Alain",
"quote_17" to "La agricultura no es solo un trabajo, es una forma de vida. - Desconocido",
"quote_18" to "El objetivo no es ser mejor que el otro hombre, sino mejor que tu yo anterior. - Dalai Lama",
"quote_19" to "La sostenibilidad se trata del futuro de nuestros hijos y nietos. - Desconocido",
"quote_20" to "El primer deber de un agricultor es dejar el suelo mejor de lo que lo encontró. - Desconocido",
"quote_21" to "Trabaja duro en silencio, deja que tu éxito sea tu ruido. - Frank Ocean",
"quote_22" to "La persistencia puede transformar el fracaso en un logro extraordinario. - Matt Biondi",
"quote_23" to "El trabajo de un agricultor nunca termina, pero las recompensas son eternas. - Desconocido",
"quote_24" to "Cada día es una nueva oportunidad para crecer. - Desconocido",
"quote_25" to "El crecimiento nunca es por pura casualidad; es el resultado de fuerzas que trabajan juntas. - James Cash Penney",
"quote_26" to "La vida sencilla es su propia recompensa. - Desconocido",
"quote_27" to "Los agricultores son la columna vertebral del mundo. - Desconocido",
"quote_28" to "Un campo es tan bueno como el hombre que lo cuida. - Desconocido",
"quote_29" to "Para un agricultor, cada semilla es una promesa. - Desconocido",
"quote_30" to "La fe es el pájaro que siente la luz cuando el amanecer aún está oscuro. - Rabindranath Tagore",
"quote_31" to "El éxito suele llegar a quienes están demasiado ocupados para buscarlo. - Henry David Thoreau",
"quote_32" to "No hay atajos para ningún lugar al que valga la pena ir. - Beverly Sills",
"quote_33" to "Cree que puedes y estarás a mitad de camino. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_34" to "Tu corazón es como un jardín. Puedes plantar flores o puedes plantar malezas. - Desconocido",
"quote_35" to "El descubrimiento de la agricultura fue el primer gran paso hacia una vida civilizada. - Arthur Keith",
"quote_36" to "Los cultivadores de la tierra son los ciudadanos más valiosos. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_37" to "El agricultor tiene que ser optimista o no seguiría siendo agricultor. - Will Rogers",
"quote_38" to "Solo el agricultor que planta semillas fielmente en la primavera recoge una cosecha en el otoño. - B.C. Forbes",
"quote_39" to "Ninguna raza puede prosperar hasta que aprenda que hay tanta dignidad en labrar un campo como en escribir un poema. - Booker T. Washington",
"quote_40" to "Si le haces cosquillas a la tierra con una azada, ella se ríe con una cosecha. - Douglas Jerrold",
"quote_41" to "La agricultura no solo da riquezas a una nación, sino las únicas riquezas que puede llamar suyas. - Samuel Johnson",
"quote_42" to "El arte de la agricultura es el arte de ser socio de Dios. - Desconocido",
"quote_43" to "Ser agricultor significa tener mucha paciencia. - Desconocido",
"quote_44" to "Todo lo que nos frena y nos obliga a tener paciencia, todo lo que nos devuelve a los ciclos lentos de la naturaleza, es una ayuda. - May Sarton",
"quote_45" to "El agricultor es un mago que produce dinero del barro. - Amit Kalantri",
"quote_46" to "El suelo es la mitad oculta de la naturaleza. - Desconocido",
"quote_47" to "Arar es la base de la agricultura. - Desconocido",
"quote_48" to "La naturaleza no se apresura, pero todo se logra. - Lao Tzu",
"quote_49" to "Quien tiene una tierra tiene un oro. - Proverbio africano",
"quote_50" to "Cuida la tierra y la tierra te cuidará a ti. - Desconocido",
"quote_51" to "Los pequeños agricultores son los héroes de nuestro sistema alimentario. - Desconocido",
"quote_52" to "La persistencia es la hermana gemela de la excelencia. Una es cuestión de calidad; la otra, de tiempo. - Marabel Morgan",
"quote_53" to "El trabajo duro es la fórmula para el éxito. - Desconocido",
"quote_54" to "El sudor del agricultor es la lluvia para las cosechas. - Desconocido",
"quote_55" to "Cuanto más duro trabajes por algo, más grande te sentirás cuando lo logres. - Desconocido",
"quote_56" to "El éxito es la suma de pequeños esfuerzos, repetidos día tras día. - Robert Collier",
"quote_57" to "Sueña en grande, trabaja duro, mantente enfocado. - Desconocido",
"quote_58" to "Los desafíos son los que hacen la vida interesante y superarlos es lo que hace que la vida tenga sentido. - Joshua J. Marine",
"quote_59" to "No esperes la oportunidad. Créala. - Desconocido",
"quote_60" to "El secreto para salir adelante es comenzar. - Mark Twain",
"quote_61" to "La calidad no es un acto, es un hábito. - Aristóteles",
"quote_62" to "Me parece que cuanto más duro trabajo, más suerte parezco tener. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_63" to "La fuerza y el crecimiento vienen solo a través del esfuerzo y la lucha continuos. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_64" to "El coraje no es tener la fuerza para seguir; es seguir cuando no tienes fuerza. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_65" to "El camino al éxito siempre está en construcción. - Lily Tomlin",
"quote_66" to "El fracaso es el condimento que le da al éxito su sabor. - Truman Capote",
"quote_67" to "No te avergüences de tus fracasos, aprende de ellos y comienza de nuevo. - Richard Branson",
"quote_68" to "Los tiempos difíciles no crean héroes. Es durante los tiempos difíciles cuando el 'héroe' dentro de nosotros se revela. - Bob Riley",
"quote_69" to "El carácter es la capacidad de llevar a cabo una buena resolución mucho después de que la emoción del momento haya pasado. - Cavett Robert",
"quote_70" to "Tu cosecha llegará si no te rindes. - Desconocido"
"quote_1" to "Ang agrikultura ang pinakamalusog, pinakakapaki-pakinabang, at pinakadangal na hanapbuhay ng tao. - George Washington",
"quote_2" to "Ang magsasaka ang tanging tao sa ating ekonomiya na bumibili ng lahat sa retail, nagbebenta ng lahat sa wholesale, at nagbabayad ng kargamento sa parehong paraan. - John F. Kennedy",
"quote_3" to "Ang pagsasaka ay isang propesyon ng pag-asa. - Brian Brett",
"quote_4" to "Ang huling layunin ng pagsasaka ay hindi ang pagpapatubo ng mga pananim, kundi ang paglilinang at pagperpekto ng mga tao. - Masanobu Fukuoka",
"quote_5" to "Ang masipag na trabaho ay nagbibigay-diin sa karakter ng mga tao: ang ilan ay naglululon ng kanilang mga manggas, ang ilan ay kumukulubot ng kanilang mga ilong, at ang ilan ay hindi sumisipot. - Sam Ewing",
"quote_6" to "Ang pagtitiyaga ay sa karakter ng tao gaya ng carbon sa bakal. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_7" to "Ang tagumpay ay hindi katapusan, ang kabiguan ay hindi nakamamatay: ang lakas ng loob na magpatuloy ang mahalaga. - Winston Churchill",
"quote_8" to "Ang tanging lugar kung saan nauuna ang tagumpay bago ang trabaho ay sa diksyunaryo. - Vidal Sassoon",
"quote_9" to "Huwag husgahan ang bawat araw sa aning iyong inaani kundi sa mga binhing iyong itinatanim. - Robert Louis Stevenson",
"quote_10" to "Ang pinakamahusay na paraan upang mahulaan ang iyong kinabukasan ay ang likhain ito. - Abraham Lincoln",
"quote_11" to "Talo ng sipag ang galing kapag ang galing ay hindi nagsisipag. - Tim Notke",
"quote_12" to "Ang pagsasaka ay mukhang napakadali kapag ang iyong araro ay isang lapis at ikaw ay nasa libu-libong milya ang layo mula sa bukid ng mais. - Dwight D. Eisenhower",
"quote_13" to "Ang mata ng amo ang nagpapataba sa baboy. - Salawikain",
"quote_14" to "Ang malalaking bagay ay nagagawa sa pamamagitan ng serye ng maliliit na bagay na pinagsama-sama. - Vincent Van Gogh",
"quote_15" to "Ang pundasyon ng bawat estado ay ang edukasyon ng kabataan nito. - Diogenes",
"quote_16" to "Ang buhay sa bukid ay isang paaralan ng pagtitiyaga. Hindi mo maaaring madaliin ang mga pananim o gumawa ng baka sa loob ng dalawang araw. - Henri Alain",
"quote_17" to "Ang pagsasaka ay hindi lamang isang trabaho, ito ay isang paraan ng pamumuhay. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_18" to "Ang layunin ay hindi ang maging mas mahusay kaysa sa ibang tao, kundi ang maging mas mahusay kaysa sa iyong dating sarili. - Dalai Lama",
"quote_19" to "Ang pagpapanatili ay tungkol sa kinabukasan ng ating mga anak at apo. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_20" to "Ang unang tungkulin ng isang magsasaka ay iwanan ang lupa nang mas maayos kaysa sa natagpuan niya ito. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_21" to "Magtrabaho nang mabuti sa katahimikan, hayaang ang iyong tagumpay ang maging ingay. - Frank Ocean",
"quote_22" to "Ang pagtitiyaga ay maaaring magbago ng kabiguan tungo sa pambihirang tagumpay. - Matt Biondi",
"quote_23" to "Ang trabaho ng magsasaka ay hindi natatapos, ngunit ang mga gantimpala ay walang hanggan. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_24" to "Ang bawat araw ay isang bagong pagkakataon upang lumago. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_25" to "Ang paglago ay hindi kailanman dahil sa pagkakataon lamang; ito ay resulta ng mga puwersang nagtutulungan. - James Cash Penney",
"quote_26" to "Ang simpleng buhay ay sarili nitong gantimpala. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_27" to "Ang mga magsasaka ang gulugod ng mundo. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_28" to "Ang isang bukid ay kasinghusay lamang ng taong nag-aalaga rito. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_29" to "Para sa isang magsasaka, ang bawat binhi ay isang pangako. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_30" to "Ang pananampalataya ay ang ibon na nakararamdam ng liwanag kapag ang bukang-liwayway ay madilim pa. - Rabindranath Tagore",
"quote_31" to "Ang tagumpay ay karaniwang dumarating sa mga masyadong abala para hanapin ito. - Henry David Thoreau",
"quote_32" to "Walang mga shortcut sa anumang lugar na karapat-dapat puntahan. - Beverly Sills",
"quote_33" to "Maniwala kang kaya mo at nasa kalagitnaan ka na. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_34" to "Ang iyong puso ay parang hardin. Maaari kang magtanim ng mga bulaklak o maaari kang magtanim ng mga damo. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_35" to "Ang pagtuklas ng agrikultura ang unang malaking hakbang tungo sa isang sibilisadong buhay. - Arthur Keith",
"quote_36" to "Ang mga tagapagtanam sa lupa ang pinakamahalagang mamamayan. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_37" to "Ang magsasaka ay kailangang maging positibo o hindi na siya mananatiling magsasaka. - Will Rogers",
"quote_38" to "Ang magsasaka lamang na tapat na nagtatanim ng mga binhi sa Tag-sibol ang umaani ng anihan sa Taglagas. - B.C. Forbes",
"quote_39" to "Walang lahing uunlad hanggang sa malaman nito na may kasingdangal ang pagbubungkal ng bukid sa pagsusulat ng tula. - Booker T. Washington",
"quote_40" to "Kung kilitiin mo ang lupa gamit ang asarol, tatawa siya nang may anihan. - Douglas Jerrold",
"quote_41" to "Ang agrikultura ay hindi lamang nagbibigay ng kayamanan sa isang bansa, kundi ang tanging kayamanan na matatawag niyang sarili. - Samuel Johnson",
"quote_42" to "Ang sining ng agrikultura ay ang sining ng pagiging kapareha ng Diyos. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_43" to "Ang pagpapakita ng magsasaka ay nangangahulugan na mayroon kang malaking pagtitiyaga. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_44" to "Ang lahat ng nagpapabagal sa atin at nagpipilit ng pagtitiyaga, lahat ng nagbabalik sa atin sa mabagal na siklo ng kalikasan, ay isang tulong. - May Sarton",
"quote_45" to "Ang magsasaka ay isang salamangkero na gumagawa ng pera mula sa putik. - Amit Kalantri",
"quote_46" to "Ang lupa ang nakatagong kalahati ng kalikasan. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_47" to "Ang pag-aararo ang pundasyon ng agrikultura. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_48" to "Ang kalikasan ay hindi nagmamadali, gayunpaman ang lahat ay nagagawa. - Lao Tzu",
"quote_49" to "Ang may lupa ay may ginto. - Salawikaing Aprikano",
"quote_50" to "Alagaan mo ang lupa at ang lupa ang mag-aalaga sa iyo. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_51" to "Ang mga maliliit na magsasaka ang mga bayani ng ating sistema ng pagkain. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_52" to "Ang pagtitiyaga ay ang kambal na kapatid ng kahusayan. Ang isa ay tungkol sa kalidad; ang isa naman ay tungkol sa oras. - Marabel Morgan",
"quote_53" to "Ang sipag ang pormula para sa tagumpay. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_54" to "Ang pawis ng magsasaka ang ulan para sa mga pananim. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_55" to "Kung mas pinaghirapan mo ang isang bagay, mas masaya ang pakiramdam mo kapag nakamit mo ito. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_56" to "Ang tagumpay ay ang kabuuan ng maliliit na pagsisikap, na inuulit araw-araw. - Robert Collier",
"quote_57" to "Mangarap nang malaki, magsipag, manatiling nakatutok. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_58" to "Ang mga hamon ang nagpapasaya sa buhay at ang pagtagumpay sa mga ito ang nagbibigay ng kahulugan sa buhay. - Joshua J. Marine",
"quote_59" to "Huwag maghintay para sa pagkakataon. Likhain ito. - Hindi Kilala",
"quote_60" to "Ang lihim ng pag-unlad ay ang pagsisimula. - Mark Twain",
"quote_61" to "Ang kalidad ay hindi isang gawa, ito ay isang ugali. - Aristotle",
"quote_62" to "Napapansin ko na kung gaano ako kasipag, tila mas sinuswerte ako. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_63" to "Ang lakas at paglago ay dumarating lamang sa pamamagitan ng tuluy-tuloy na pagsisikap at pakikibaka. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_64" to "Ang lakas ng loob ay hindi ang pagkakaroon ng lakas upang magpatuloy; ito ay ang pagpapatuloy kapag wala ka nang lakas. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_65" to "Ang daan patungo sa tagumpay ay palaging nasa ilalim ng konstruksyon. - Lily Tomlin",
"quote_66" to "Ang kabiguan ay ang pampalasa na nagbibigay ng lasa sa tagumpay. - Truman Capote",
"quote_67" to "Huwag kang mapahiya sa iyong mga kabiguan, matuto mula sa mga ito at magsimulang muli. - Richard Branson",
"quote_68" to "Ang mahihirap na panahon ay hindi lumilikha ng mga bayani. Ito ay sa panahon ng mahihirap na sandali na ang 'bayani' sa loob natin ay nahahayag. - Bob Riley",
"quote_69" to "Ang karakter ay ang kakayahang isagawa ang isang mabuting resolusyon matagal na matapos lumipas ang pananabik sa sandaling iyon. - Cavett Robert",
"quote_70" to "Ang iyong anihan ay darating kung hindi ka susuko. - Hindi Kilala"
"quote_1" to "Nông nghiệp là nghề nghiệp lành mạnh nhất, hữu ích nhất và cao quý nhất của con người. - George Washington",
"quote_2" to "Người nông dân là người duy nhất trong nền kinh tế của chúng ta mua mọi thứ với giá bán lẻ, bán mọi thứ với giá bán buôn và trả tiền cước vận chuyển cả hai chiều. - John F. Kennedy",
"quote_3" to "Nông nghiệp là một nghề nghiệp của hy vọng. - Brian Brett",
"quote_4" to "Mục tiêu cuối cùng của canh tác không phải là trồng cây, mà là sự nuôi dưỡng và hoàn thiện con người. - Masanobu Fukuoka",
"quote_5" to "Làm việc chăm chỉ làm nổi bật tính cách của con người: một số người xắn tay áo, một số người hếch mũi và một số người hoàn toàn không xuất hiện. - Sam Ewing",
"quote_6" to "Sự kiên trì đối với tính cách của con người giống như carbon đối với thép. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_7" to "Thành công không phải là cuối cùng, thất bại không phải là tử vong: lòng can đảm để tiếp tục mới là điều quan trọng. - Winston Churchill",
"quote_8" to "Nơi duy nhất mà thành công đứng trước công việc là trong từ điển. - Vidal Sassoon",
"quote_9" to "Đừng đánh giá mỗi ngày qua vụ thu hoạch bạn gặt hái được mà hãy đánh giá qua những hạt giống bạn gieo trồng. - Robert Louis Stevenson",
"quote_10" to "Cách tốt nhất để dự đoán tương lai của bạn là tạo ra nó. - Abraham Lincoln",
"quote_11" to "Sự chăm chỉ đánh bại tài năng khi tài năng không làm việc chăm chỉ. - Tim Notke",
"quote_12" to "Nông nghiệp trông có vẻ rất dễ dàng khi cái cày của bạn là một cây bút chì và bạn cách cánh đồng ngô một ngàn dặm. - Dwight D. Eisenhower",
"quote_13" to "Mắt của chủ làm béo con heo. - Ngạn ngữ",
"quote_14" to "Những điều lớn lao được thực hiện bởi một loạt những điều nhỏ bé được tập hợp lại với nhau. - Vincent Van Gogh",
"quote_15" to "Nền tảng của mọi quốc gia là giáo dục thanh thiếu niên. - Diogenes",
"quote_16" to "Cuộc sống trong trang trại là một ngôi trường của lòng kiên nhẫn. Bạn không thể thúc giục cây trồng hay tạo ra một con bò trong hai ngày. - Henri Alain",
"quote_17" to "Nông nghiệp không chỉ là một công việc, đó là một lối sống. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_18" to "Mục tiêu không phải là tốt hơn người khác, mà là tốt hơn chính bản thân mình trước đây. - Đạt Lai Lạt Ma",
"quote_19" to "Sự bền vững là về tương lai của con cái và cháu chắt chúng ta. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_20" to "Nhiệm vụ đầu tiên của một người nông dân là để lại đất đai tốt hơn so với khi anh ta tìm thấy nó. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_21" to "Làm việc chăm chỉ trong im lặng, hãy để thành công của bạn là tiếng ồn của bạn. - Frank Ocean",
"quote_22" to "Sự kiên trì có thể biến thất bại thành thành tựu phi thường. - Matt Biondi",
"quote_23" to "Công việc của một người nông dân không bao giờ kết thúc, nhưng phần thưởng là vĩnh cửu. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_24" to "Mỗi ngày là một cơ hội mới để phát triển. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_25" to "Sự tăng trưởng không bao giờ là do ngẫu nhiên; nó là kết quả của các lực lượng làm việc cùng nhau. - James Cash Penney",
"quote_26" to "Cuộc sống giản đơn là phần thưởng của riêng nó. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_27" to "Nông dân là xương sống của thế giới. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_28" to "Một cánh đồng chỉ tốt bằng người chăm sóc nó. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_29" to "Đối với một người nông dân, mỗi hạt giống là một lời hứa. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_30" to "Đức tin là con chim cảm nhận được ánh sáng khi bình minh vẫn còn tối. - Rabindranath Tagore",
"quote_31" to "Thành công thường đến với những người quá bận rộn để tìm kiếm nó. - Henry David Thoreau",
"quote_32" to "Không có đường tắt đến bất cứ nơi nào xứng đáng để đi. - Beverly Sills",
"quote_33" to "Hãy tin rằng bạn có thể và bạn đã đi được nửa đường. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_34" to "Trái tim bạn giống như một khu vườn. Bạn có thể trồng hoa hoặc bạn có thể trồng cỏ dại. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_35" to "Sự khám phá ra nông nghiệp là bước tiến lớn đầu tiên hướng tới một cuộc sống văn minh. - Arthur Keith",
"quote_36" to "Những người canh tác đất đai là những công dân có giá trị nhất. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_37" to "Người nông dân phải là một người lạc quan, nếu không anh ta sẽ không còn là một người nông dân nữa. - Will Rogers",
"quote_38" to "Chỉ có người nông dân trung thành gieo hạt vào mùa xuân mới gặt hái được vụ thu hoạch vào mùa thu. - B.C. Forbes",
"quote_39" to "Không có chủng tộc nào có thể thịnh vượng cho đến khi họ học được rằng có nhiều phẩm giá trong việc cày ruộng cũng như trong việc viết một bài thơ. - Booker T. Washington",
"quote_40" to "Nếu bạn thọc lét đất đai bằng một cái cuốc, cô ấy sẽ cười bằng một vụ thu hoạch. - Douglas Jerrold",
"quote_41" to "Nông nghiệp không chỉ mang lại sự giàu có cho một quốc gia, mà là sự giàu có duy nhất mà quốc gia đó có thể gọi là của riêng mình. - Samuel Johnson",
"quote_42" to "Nghệ thuật nông nghiệp là nghệ thuật làm đối tác với Chúa. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_43" to "Trở thành một nông dân có nghĩa là bạn có rất nhiều sự kiên nhẫn. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_44" to "Mọi thứ làm chúng ta chậm lại và buộc chúng ta phải kiên nhẫn, mọi thứ đưa chúng ta trở lại chu kỳ chậm chạp của thiên nhiên, đều là một sự trợ giúp. - May Sarton",
"quote_45" to "Người nông dân là một ảo thuật gia tạo ra tiền từ bùn đất. - Amit Kalantri",
"quote_46" to "Đất là một nửa ẩn giấu của thiên nhiên. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_47" to "Cày ruộng là nền tảng của nông nghiệp. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_48" to "Thiên nhiên không vội vã, nhưng mọi thứ đều hoàn thành. - Lão Tử",
"quote_49" to "Người có đất là có vàng. - Ngạn ngữ Châu Phi",
"quote_50" to "Hãy chăm sóc đất đai và đất đai sẽ chăm sóc bạn. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_51" to "Những người nông dân quy mô nhỏ là những anh hùng trong hệ thống thực phẩm của chúng ta. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_52" to "Sự kiên trì là chị em song sinh của sự xuất sắc. Một cái là vấn đề chất lượng; cái kia là vấn đề thời gian. - Marabel Morgan",
"quote_53" to "Làm việc chăm chỉ là công thức cho thành công. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_54" to "Mồ hôi của người nông dân là mưa cho mùa màng. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_55" to "Bạn càng làm việc chăm chỉ cho một điều gì đó, bạn sẽ càng cảm thấy tuyệt vời hơn khi đạt được nó. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_56" to "Thành công là tổng của những nỗ lực nhỏ, được lặp đi lặp lại ngày này qua ngày khác. - Robert Collier",
"quote_57" to "Mơ lớn, làm việc chăm chỉ, giữ tập trung. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_58" to "Thử thách là những gì làm cho cuộc sống trở nên thú vị và vượt qua chúng là những gì làm cho cuộc sống có ý nghĩa. - Joshua J. Marine",
"quote_59" to "Đừng chờ đợi cơ hội. Hãy tạo ra nó. - Khuyết danh",
"quote_60" to "Bí mật của việc tiến lên phía trước là bắt đầu. - Mark Twain",
"quote_61" to "Chất lượng không phải là một hành động, nó là một thói quen. - Aristotle",
"quote_62" to "Tôi thấy rằng tôi càng làm việc chăm chỉ, tôi càng gặp nhiều may mắn. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_63" to "Sức mạnh và sự tăng trưởng chỉ đến thông qua nỗ lực và đấu tranh liên tục. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_64" to "Can đảm không phải là có sức mạnh để tiếp tục; đó là tiếp tục khi bạn không còn sức mạnh. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_65" to "Con đường đến thành công luôn luôn được xây dựng. - Lily Tomlin",
"quote_66" to "Thất bại là gia vị mang lại hương vị cho thành công. - Truman Capote",
"quote_67" to "Đừng xấu hổ bởi những thất bại của bạn, hãy học hỏi từ chúng và bắt đầu lại. - Richard Branson",
"quote_68" to "Những thời điểm khó khăn không tạo ra anh hùng. Chính trong những thời điểm khó khăn, 'anh hùng' bên trong chúng ta mới được bộc lộ. - Bob Riley",
"quote_69" to "Tính cách là khả năng thực hiện một quyết tâm tốt lâu sau khi sự phấn khích của thời điểm đó đã qua đi. - Cavett Robert",
"quote_70" to "Vụ thu hoạch của bạn sẽ đến nếu bạn không bỏ cuộc. - Khuyết danh"
"quote_1" to "เกษตรกรรมเป็นการจ้างงานที่ดีต่อสุขภาพ มีประโยชน์ และสูงส่งที่สุดของมนุษย์ - จอร์จ วอชิงตัน",
"quote_2" to "เกษตรกรเป็นคนคนเดียวในเศรษฐกิจของเราที่ซื้อทุกอย่างในราคาปลีก ขายทุกอย่างในราคาส่ง และจ่ายค่าขนส่งทั้งสองทาง - จอห์น เอฟ. เคนเนดี",
"quote_3" to "การทำฟาร์มคืออาชีพแห่งความหวัง - ไบรอัน เบรตต์",
"quote_4" to "เป้าหมายสูงสุดของการทำฟาร์มไม่ใช่การปลูกพืช แต่เป็นการบ่มเพาะและความสมบูรณ์แบบของมนุษย์ - มาซาโนบุ ฟุกุโอกะ",
"quote_5" to "งานหนักช่วยส่องสว่างตัวตนของผู้คน: บางคนม้วนแขนเสื้อขึ้น บางคนทำจมูกย่น และบางคนไม่ปรากฏตัวเลย - แซม อีวิง",
"quote_6" to "ความพากเพียรมีความสำคัญต่ออุปนิสัยของมนุษย์ เหมือนกับคาร์บอนที่มีต่อเหล็กกล้า - นโปเลียน ฮิลล์",
"quote_7" to "ความสำเร็จไม่ใช่จุดสิ้นสุด ความล้มเหลวไม่ใช่เรื่องคอขาดบาดตาย: ความกล้าที่จะเดินหน้าต่อไปต่างหากที่สำคัญ - วินสตัน เชอร์ชิลล์",
"quote_8" to "ที่เดียวที่ความสำเร็จมาก่อนการทำงานคือในพจนานุกรม - วิดัล แซสซูน",
"quote_9" to "อย่าตัดสินแต่ละวันจากพืชผลที่คุณเก็บเกี่ยว แต่ให้ตัดสินจากเมล็ดพันธุ์ที่คุณหว่านลงไป - โรเบิร์ต หลุยส์ สตีเวนสัน",
"quote_10" to "วิธีที่ดีที่สุดในการทำนายอนาคตของคุณคือการสร้างมันขึ้นมา - อับราฮัม ลินคอล์น",
"quote_11" to "งานหนักชนะพรสวรรค์ เมื่อพรสวรรค์ไม่ทำงานหนัก - ทิม น็อตเก้",
"quote_12" to "การทำฟาร์มดูเหมือนจะง่ายมากเมื่อคันไถของคุณคือดินสอ และคุณอยู่ห่างจากทุ่งข้าวโพดหนึ่งพันไมล์ - ดไวต์ ดี. ไอเซนฮาวร์",
"quote_13" to "สายตาของเจ้าของทำให้หมูอ้วน - สุภาษิต",
"quote_14" to "สิ่งที่ยิ่งใหญ่สำเร็จได้ด้วยสิ่งเล็กน้อยหลายอย่างที่นำมารวมกัน - วินเซนต์ แวน โก๊ะ",
"quote_15" to "รากฐานของทุกรัฐคือการศึกษาของเยาวชน - ไดโอจินีส",
"quote_16" to "ชีวิตในฟาร์มคือโรงเรียนแห่งความอดทน คุณไม่สามารถเร่งพืชผลหรือสร้างวัวในสองวันได้ - อองรี อาลัน",
"quote_17" to "การทำฟาร์มไม่ใช่แค่เรื่องงาน แต่มันคือวิถีชีวิต - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_18" to "เป้าหมายไม่ใช่การเก่งกว่าคนอื่น แต่เป็นการเก่งกว่าตัวคุณในอดีต - ดาไล ลามะ",
"quote_19" to "ความยั่งยืนคือเรื่องของอนาคตของลูกหลานเรา - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_20" to "หน้าที่แรกของเกษตรกรคือการทำให้ดินดีขึ้นกว่าตอนที่เขาพบมัน - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_21" to "ทำงานหนักอย่างเงียบเชียบ และปล่อยให้ความสำเร็จส่งเสียงแทนคุณ - แฟรงก์ โอเชียน",
"quote_22" to "ความพากเพียรสามารถเปลี่ยนความล้มเหลวให้เป็นความสำเร็จที่ยิ่งใหญ่ได้ - แมตต์ บิออนดิ",
"quote_23" to "งานของเกษตรกรไม่มีวันสิ้นสุด แต่ผลตอบแทนนั้นเป็นนิรันดร์ - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_24" to "ทุกวันคือโอกาสใหม่ในการเติบโต - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_25" to "การเติบโตไม่ได้เกิดขึ้นโดยบังเอิญ แต่มันคือผลลัพธ์ของพลังที่ทำงานร่วมกัน - เจมส์ แคช เพนนีย์",
"quote_26" to "ชีวิตที่เรียบง่ายคือรางวัลในตัวมันเอง - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_27" to "เกษตรกรคือกระดูกสันหลังของโลก - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_28" to "ทุ่งนาจะดีได้ก็ต่อเมื่อมีคนที่คอยดูแลมันเป็นอย่างดี - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_29" to "สำหรับเกษตรกร ทุกเมล็ดพันธุ์คือคำสัญญา - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_30" to "ศรัทธาคือวิกที่สัมผัสได้ถึงแสงสว่างในขณะที่รุ่งอรุณยังมืดมิด - รพินทรนาถ ฐากูร",
"quote_31" to "ความสำเร็จมักมาหาผู้ที่ยุ่งเกินกว่าจะมองหาตัวมัน - เฮนรี เดวิด โธโร",
"quote_32" to "ไม่มีทางลัดไปยังสถานที่ใดก็ตามที่คุ้มค่าแก่การไป - เบเวอร์ลี ซิลส์",
"quote_33" to "เชื่อว่าคุณทำได้ และคุณก็มาได้ครึ่งทางแล้ว - ธีโอดอร์ รูสเวลต์",
"quote_34" to "หัวใจของคุณก็เหมือนสวน คุณสามารถปลูกดอกไม้หรือจะปลูกวัชพืชก็ได้ - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_35" to "การค้นพบเกษตรกรรมเป็นก้าวแรกที่ยิ่งใหญ่สู่ชีวิตที่มีอารยธรรม - อาร์เธอร์ คีธ",
"quote_36" to "ผู้เพาะปลูกบนผืนดินคือพลเมืองที่มีค่าที่สุด - โธมัส เจฟเฟอร์สัน",
"quote_37" to "เกษตรกรต้องเป็นคนมองโลกในแง่ดี ไม่อย่างนั้นเขาคงเลิกเป็นเกษตรกรไปแล้ว - วิล โรเจอร์ส",
"quote_38" to "มีเพียงเกษตรกรที่ปลูกเมล็ดพันธุ์อย่างซื่อสัตย์ในฤดูใบไม้ผลิเท่านั้นที่จะได้เก็บเกี่ยวผลผลิตในฤดูใบไม้ร่วง - บี.ซี. ฟอร์บส์",
"quote_39" to "ไม่มีเผ่าพันธุ์ใดเจริญรุ่งเรืองได้จนกว่าจะเรียนรู้ว่าการทำนามีเกียรติพอๆ กับการเขียนบทกวี - บุ๊คเกอร์ ที. วอชิงตัน",
"quote_40" to "หากคุณจี้แผ่นดินด้วยจอบ เธอจะหัวเราะออกมาเป็นผลผลิต - ดักลาส เจอร์โรลด์",
"quote_41" to "เกษตรกรรมไม่เพียงแต่ให้ความมั่งคั่งแก่ชาติ แต่ยังเป็นความมั่งคั่งเพียงอย่างเดียวที่ชาติเรียกได้ว่าเป็นของตนเอง - ซามูเอล จอห์นสัน",
"quote_42" to "ศิลปะแห่งเกษตรกรรมคือศิลปะแห่งการเป็นหุ้นส่วนกับพระเจ้า - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_43" to "การเป็นเกษตรกรหมายความว่าคุณต้องมีความอดทนอย่างมาก - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_44" to "ทุกสิ่งที่ทำให้เราช้าลงและบังคับให้เราอดทน ทุกสิ่งที่ทำให้เรากลับสู่รอบวงจรที่เชื่องช้าของธรรมชาติ คือตัวช่วย - เมย์ ซาร์ตัน",
"quote_45" to "เกษตรกรคือนักมายากลที่เสกเงินขึ้นมาจากโคลนตม - อมิต กาลันตรี",
"quote_46" to "ดินคือครึ่งหนึ่งของธรรมชาติที่ซ่อนอยู่ - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_47" to "การไถคือรากฐานของเกษตรกรรม - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_48" to "ธรรมชาติไม่เคยรีบร้อน แต่ทุกสิ่งก็สำเร็จลุล่วง - เล่าจื๊อ",
"quote_49" to "ผู้ที่มีที่ดินย่อมมีทองคำ - สุภาษิตแอฟริกัน",
"quote_50" to "ดูแลที่ดิน แล้วที่ดินจะดูแลคุณ - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_51" to "เกษตรกรรายย่อยคือวีรบุรุษในระบบอาหารของเรา - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_52" to "ความพากเพียรคือฝาแฝดของความยอดเยี่ยม อย่างหนึ่งคือเรื่องของคุณภาพ อีกอย่างหนึ่งคือเรื่องของเวลา - มาราเบล มอร์แกน",
"quote_53" to "งานหนักคือสูตรสำเร็จของความสำเร็จ - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_54" to "หยาดเหงื่อของเกษตรกรคือน้ำฝนสำหรับพืชผล - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_55" to "ยิ่งคุณทำงานหนักเพื่อบางสิ่งมากเท่าไหร่ คุณจะยิ่งรู้สึกดีมากขึ้นเท่านั้นเมื่อคุณทำสำเร็จ - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_56" to "ความสำเร็จคือผลรวมของความพยายามเล็กๆ ที่ทำซ้ำแล้วซ้ำเล่าวันแล้ววันเล่า - โรเบิร์ต คอลลิเยอร์",
"quote_57" to "ฝันให้ใหญ่ ทำงานหนัก และมีสมาธิ - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_58" to "ความท้าทายคือสิ่งที่ทำให้ชีวิตน่าสนใจ และการเอาชนะมันคือสิ่งที่ทำให้ชีวิตมีความหมาย - โจชัว เจ. มารีน",
"quote_59" to "อย่ารอโอกาส แต่จงสร้างมันขึ้นมา - ไม่ระบุชื่อ",
"quote_60" to "ความลับของการก้าวไปข้างหน้าคือการเริ่มลงมือทำ - มาร์ก ทเวน",
"quote_61" to "คุณภาพไม่ใช่การกระทำ แต่มันคือนิสัย - อริสโตเติล",
"quote_62" to "ฉันพบว่ายิ่งฉันทำงานหนักเท่าไหร่ ฉันก็ยิ่งดูเหมือนจะมีโชคมากขึ้นเท่านั้น - โธมัส เจฟเฟอร์สัน",
"quote_63" to "ความเข้มแข็งและการเติบโตมาจากการพยายามและการต่อสู้ที่ต่อเนื่องเท่านั้น - นโปเลียน ฮิลล์",
"quote_64" to "ความกล้าหาญไม่ใช่การมีกำลังเพื่อที่จะไปต่อ แต่มันคือการไปต่อในเวลาที่คุณไม่มีกำลังเหลือแล้ว - ธีโอดอร์ รูสเวลต์",
"quote_65" to "ถนนสู่ความสำเร็จอยู่ระหว่างการก่อสร้างเสมอ - ลิลลี ทอมลิน",
"quote_66" to "ความล้มเหลวคือเครื่องปรุงที่ทำให้ความสำเร็จมีรสชาติ - ทรูแมน คาโพตี",
"quote_67" to "อย่าอายในความล้มเหลว จงเรียนรู้จากมันและเริ่มใหม่ - ริชาร์ด แบรนสัน",
"quote_68" to "ช่วงเวลาที่ยากลำบากไม่ได้สร้างวีรบุรุษ แต่เป็นช่วงเวลาที่ยากลำบากที่ 'วีรบุรุษ' ในตัวเราจะถูกเปิดเผย - บ็อบ ไรลีย์",
"quote_69" to "ตัวตนคือความสามารถในการทำตามความตั้งใจที่ดีได้นานหลังจากที่ความตื่นเต้นในขณะนั้นผ่านพ้นไปแล้ว - คาเวตต์ โรเบิร์ต",
"quote_70" to "ผลผลิตของคุณจะมาถึงหากคุณไม่ยอมแพ้ - ไม่ระบุชื่อ"
"quote_1" to "A agricultura é o emprego mais saudável, mais útil e mais nobre do homem. - George Washington",
"quote_2" to "O agricultor é o único homem na nossa economia que compra tudo a retalho, vende tudo por atacado e paga o frete nos dois sentidos. - John F. Kennedy",
"quote_3" to "A agricultura é uma profissão de esperança. - Brian Brett",
"quote_4" to "O objetivo final de la agricultura não é o cultivo de colheitas, mas o cultivo e o aperfeiçoamento dos seres humanos. - Masanobu Fukuoka",
"quote_5" to "O trabalho árduo destaca o caráter das pessoas: alguns arregaçam as mangas, alguns torcem o nariz e alguns nem sequer aparecem. - Sam Ewing",
"quote_6" to "A persistência está para o caráter do homem como o carbono está para o aço. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_7" to "O sucesso não é definitivo, o fracasso não é fatal: o que conta é a coragem de continuar. - Winston Churchill",
"quote_8" to "O único lugar onde o sucesso vem antes do trabalho é no dicionário. - Vidal Sassoon",
"quote_9" to "Não julgue cada dia pela colheita que você colhe, mas pelas sementes que você planta. - Robert Louis Stevenson",
"quote_10" to "A melhor maneira de prever o seu futuro é criá-lo. - Abraham Lincoln",
"quote_11" to "O trabalho árduo vence o talento quando o talento não trabalha arduamente. - Tim Notke",
"quote_12" to "A agricultura parece muito fácil quando o seu arado é um lápis e você está a mil milhas do milharal. - Dwight D. Eisenhower",
"quote_13" to "O olho do dono é que engorda o porco. - Provérbio",
"quote_14" to "Grandes coisas são feitas por uma série de pequenas coisas reunidas. - Vincent Van Gogh",
"quote_15" to "A base de todo estado é a educação de sua juventude. - Diógenes",
"quote_16" to "A vida em uma fazenda é uma escola de paciência. Você não pode apressar as colheitas ou fazer um boi em dois dias. - Henri Alain",
"quote_17" to "A agricultura não é apenas um trabalho, é um modo de vida. - Desconhecido",
"quote_18" to "O objetivo não é ser melhor do que o outro homem, mas do que o seu eu anterior. - Dalai Lama",
"quote_19" to "Sustentabilidade é sobre o futuro de nossos filhos e netos. - Desconhecido",
"quote_20" to "O primeiro dever de um agricultor é deixar o solo melhor do que o encontrou. - Desconhecido",
"quote_21" to "Trabalhe duro em silêncio, deixe seu sucesso ser seu ruído. - Frank Ocean",
"quote_22" to "A persistência pode transformar o fracasso em uma conquista extraordinária. - Matt Biondi",
"quote_23" to "O trabalho de um agricultor nunca termina, mas as recompensas são eternas. - Desconhecido",
"quote_24" to "Cada dia é uma nova oportunidade de crescer. - Desconhecido",
"quote_25" to "O crescimento nunca é por mero acaso; é o resultado de forças trabalhando juntas. - James Cash Penney",
"quote_26" to "A vida simples é sua própria recompensa. - Desconhecido",
"quote_27" to "Os agricultores são a espinha dorsal do mundo. - Desconhecido",
"quote_28" to "Um campo é tão bom quanto o homem que cuida dele. - Desconhecido",
"quote_29" to "Para um agricultor, cada semente é uma promessa. - Desconhecido",
"quote_30" to "A fé é o pássaro que sente la luz quando o amanhecer ainda está escuro. - Rabindranath Tagore",
"quote_31" to "O sucesso geralmente vem para aqueles que estão ocupados demais para procurar por ele. - Henry David Thoreau",
"quote_32" to "Não há atalhos para nenhum lugar que valha a pena ir. - Beverly Sills",
"quote_33" to "Acredite que você pode e você já está no meio do caminho. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_34" to "Seu coração é como um jardim. Você pode plantar flores ou pode plantar ervas daninhas. - Desconhecido",
"quote_35" to "A descoberta da agricultura foi o primeiro grande passo em direção a uma vida civilizada. - Arthur Keith",
"quote_36" to "Cultivadores da terra são os cidadãos mais valiosos. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_37" to "O agricultor tem que ser um otimista ou não continuaria sendo um agricultor. - Will Rogers",
"quote_38" to "É apenas o agricultor que fielmente planta sementes na Primavera, que colhe uma colheita no Outono. - B.C. Forbes",
"quote_39" to "Nenhuma raça pode prosperar até aprender que há tanta dignidade em cultivar um campo quanto em escrever um poema. - Booker T. Washington",
"quote_40" to "Se você fizer cócegas na terra com uma enxada, ela ri com uma colheita. - Douglas Jerrold",
"quote_41" to "A agricultura não apenas dá riquezas a uma nação, mas as únicas riquezas que ela pode chamar de suas. - Samuel Johnson",
"quote_42" to "A arte da agricultura é a arte de ser um parceiro de Deus. - Desconhecido",
"quote_43" to "Ser agricultor significa que você tem muita paciência. - Desconhecido",
"quote_44" to "Tudo o que nos atrasa e nos força à paciência, tudo o que nos coloca de volta nos ciclos lentos da natureza, é uma ajuda. - May Sarton",
"quote_45" to "O agricultor é um mágico que produz dinheiro da lama. - Amit Kalantri",
"quote_46" to "O solo é a metade escondida da natureza. - Desconhecido",
"quote_47" to "Arar é a base da agricultura. - Desconhecido",
"quote_48" to "A natureza não tem pressa, mas tudo é realizado. - Lao Tzu",
"quote_49" to "Quem tem uma terra tem um ouro. - Provérbio africano",
"quote_50" to "Cuide da terra e a terra cuidará de você. - Desconhecido",
"quote_51" to "Pequenos agricultores são os heróis do nosso sistema alimentar. - Desconhecido",
"quote_52" to "A persistência é a irmã gêmea da excelência. Uma é uma questão de qualidade; a outra, uma questão de tempo. - Marabel Morgan",
"quote_53" to "O trabalho árduo é a fórmula para o sucesso. - Desconhecido",
"quote_54" to "O suor do agricultor é a chuva para as colheitas. - Desconhecido",
"quote_55" to "Quanto mais você trabalhar por algo, melhor você se sentirá quando o alcançar. - Desconhecido",
"quote_56" to "O sucesso é a soma de pequenos esforços, repetidos dia após dia. - Robert Collier",
"quote_57" to "Sonhe alto, trabalhe duro, mantenha o foco. - Desconhecido",
"quote_58" to "Desafios são o que tornam a vida interessante e superá-los é o que torna a vida significativa. - Joshua J. Marine",
"quote_59" to "Não espere pela oportunidade. Crie-a. - Desconhecido",
"quote_60" to "O segredo de seguir em frente é começar. - Mark Twain",
"quote_61" to "A qualidade não é um ato, é um hábito. - Aristóteles",
"quote_62" to "Descobri que quanto mais eu trabalho, mais sorte eu pareço ter. - Thomas Jefferson",
"quote_63" to "A força e o crescimento vêm apenas através de esforço e luta contínuos. - Napoleon Hill",
"quote_64" to "Coragem não é ter força para continuar; é continuar quando você não tem força. - Theodore Roosevelt",
"quote_65" to "A estrada para o sucesso está sempre em construção. - Lily Tomlin",
"quote_66" to "O fracasso é o condimento que dá ao sucesso o seu sabor. - Truman Capote",
"quote_67" to "Não se sinta envergonhado por seus fracassos, aprenda com eles e comece de novo. - Richard Branson",
"quote_68" to "Tempos difíceis não criam heróis. É durante os tempos difíceis que o 'herói' dentro de nós é revelado. - Bob Riley",
"quote_69" to "Caráter é a capacidade de realizar uma boa resolução muito depois que a emoção do momento passou. - Cavett Robert",
"quote_70" to "Sua colheita virá se você não desistir. - Desconhecido"
"quote_1" to "कृषि मनुष्य का सबसे स्वस्थ, सबसे उपयोगी और सबसे महान व्यवसाय है। - जॉर्ज वाशिंगटन",
"quote_2" to "किसान हमारी अर्थव्यवस्था में अकेला ऐसा व्यक्ति है जो सब कुछ खुदरा में खरीदता है, सब कुछ थोक में बेचता है, और दोनों तरफ का भाड़ा देता है। - जॉन एफ. कैनेडी",
"quote_3" to "खेती आशा का पेशा है। - ब्रायन ब्रेट",
"quote_4" to "खेती का अंतिम लक्ष्य फसलों को उगाना नहीं है, बल्कि मनुष्यों का संवर्धन और पूर्णता है। - मासानोबू फुकुओका",
"quote_5" to "कड़ी मेहनत लोगों के चरित्र को उजागर करती है: कुछ अपनी आस्तीनें चढ़ा लेते हैं, कुछ अपनी नाक सिकोड़ लेते हैं, और कुछ बिल्कुल भी सामने नहीं आते। - सैम इविंग",
"quote_6" to "दृढ़ता मनुष्य के चरित्र के लिए वैसी ही है जैसे स्टील के लिए कार्बन। - नेपोलियन हिल",
"quote_7" to "सफलता अंतिम नहीं है, असफलता घातक नहीं है: जो मायने रखता है वह जारी रखने का साहस है। - विंस्टन चर्चिल",
"quote_8" to "डिक्शनरी ही एकमात्र ऐसी जगह है जहाँ सफलता काम से पहले आती है। - विडाल सैसून",
"quote_9" to "प्रत्येक दिन को अपनी काटी गई फसल से नहीं बल्कि अपने द्वारा बोए गए बीजों से आंकें। - रॉबर्ट लुई स्टीवेन्सन",
"quote_10" to "अपने भविष्य की भविष्यवाणी करने का सबसे अच्छा तरीका इसे बनाना है। - अब्राहम लिंकन",
"quote_11" to "जब प्रतिभा कड़ी मेहनत नहीं करती, तो कड़ी मेहनत प्रतिभा को मात दे देती है। - टिम नॉटके",
"quote_12" to "खेती करना तब बहुत आसान लगता है जब आपका हल एक पेंसिल हो और आप मक्के के खेत से हजार मील दूर हों। - ड्वाइट डी. आइजनहावर",
"quote_13" to "मालिक की नजर ही सुअर को मोटा करती है। - कहावत",
"quote_14" to "महान कार्य एक साथ लाई गई छोटी-छोटी चीजों की श्रृंखला द्वारा किए जाते हैं। - विंसेंट वैन गॉग",
"quote_15" to "हर राज्य की नींव उसके युवाओं की शिक्षा है। - डायोजनीज",
"quote_16" to "फार्म पर जीवन धैर्य की एक पाठशाला है। आप फसलों में जल्दबाजी नहीं कर सकते या दो दिनों में बैल नहीं बना सकते। - हेनरी एलेन",
"quote_17" to "खेती केवल एक काम नहीं है, यह जीने का एक तरीका है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_18" to "लक्ष्य दूसरे व्यक्ति से बेहतर होना नहीं है, बल्कि अपने पिछले स्वरूप से बेहतर होना है। - दलाई लामा",
"quote_19" to "स्थायित्व हमारे बच्चों और पोते-पोतियों के भविष्य के बारे में है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_20" to "किसान का पहला कर्तव्य मिट्टी को उससे बेहतर स्थिति में छोड़ना है जैसा उसने उसे पाया था। - अज्ञात",
"quote_21" to "शांति से कड़ी मेहनत करें, अपनी सफलता को शोर मचाने दें। - फ्रैंक ओशन",
"quote_22" to "दृढ़ता असफलता को असाधारण उपलब्धि में बदल सकती है। - मैट बियोंडी",
"quote_23" to "एक किसान का काम कभी पूरा नहीं होता, लेकिन पुरस्कार शाश्वत होते हैं। - अज्ञात",
"quote_24" to "हर दिन बढ़ने का एक नया अवसर है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_25" to "विकास कभी भी केवल संयोग से नहीं होता; यह एक साथ काम करने वाली शक्तियों का परिणाम है। - जेम्स कैश पेनी",
"quote_26" to "सादा जीवन अपने आप में एक पुरस्कार है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_27" to "किसान दुनिया की रीढ़ हैं। - अज्ञात",
"quote_28" to "एक खेत उतना ही अच्छा होता है जितना उसे सँभालने वाला आदमी। - अज्ञात",
"quote_29" to "एक किसान के लिए, हर बीज एक वादा है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_30" to "विश्वास वह पक्षी है जो रोशनी को महसूस करता है जब भोर अभी भी अंधेरी होती है। - रवींद्रनाथ टैगोर",
"quote_31" to "सफलता आमतौर पर उन लोगों के पास आती है जो इसे खोजने के लिए बहुत व्यस्त होते हैं। - हेनरी डेविड थोरो",
"quote_32" to "जाने लायक किसी भी स्थान के लिए कोई छोटा रास्ता नहीं है। - बेवर्ली सिल्स",
"quote_33" to "विश्वास करें कि आप कर सकते हैं और आप आधे रास्ते तक पहुँच गए हैं। - थियोडोर रूजवेल्ट",
"quote_34" to "आपका दिल एक बगीचे की तरह है। आप फूल लगा सकते हैं या खरपतवार उगा सकते हैं। - अज्ञात",
"quote_35" to "कृषि की खोज सभ्य जीवन की ओर पहला बड़ा कदम था। - आर्थर कीथ",
"quote_36" to "मिट्टी जोतने वाले सबसे मूल्यवान नागरिक होते हैं। - थॉमस जेफरसन",
"quote_37" to "किसान को आशावादी होना चाहिए वरना वह अभी भी किसान नहीं होता। - विल रोजर्स",
"quote_38" to "केवल वही किसान जो वसंत ऋतु में ईमानदारी से बीज बोता है, शरद ऋतु में फसल काटता है। - बी.सी. फोर्ब्स",
"quote_39" to "कोई भी जाति तब तक समृद्ध नहीं हो सकती जब तक वह यह न सीख ले कि खेत जोतने में उतनी ही गरिमा है जितनी कविता लिखने में। - बुकर टी. वाशिंगटन",
"quote_40" to "यदि आप कुदाल से धरती को गुदगुदाते हैं तो वह फसल के रूप में हंसती है। - डगलस जेरोल्ड",
"quote_41" to "कृषि न केवल एक राष्ट्र को धन देती है, बल्कि एकमात्र ऐसा धन है जिसे वह अपना कह सकती है। - सैमुअल जॉनसन",
"quote_42" to "कृषि की कला ईश्वर के साथ भागीदार होने की कला है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_43" to "किसान होने का मतलब है कि आपके पास बहुत धैर्य है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_44" to "वह सब कुछ जो हमें धीमा करता है और धैर्य के लिए मजबूर करता है, वह सब कुछ जो हमें प्रकृति के धीमे चक्रों में वापस ले जाता है, एक मदद है। - मे सार्टन",
"quote_45" to "किसान एक जादूगर है जो कीचड़ से पैसा निकालता है। - अमित कलंत्री",
"quote_46" to "मिट्टी प्रकृति का छिपा हुआ आधा हिस्सा है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_47" to "हल चलाना कृषि की नींव है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_48" to "प्रकृति कभी जल्दबाजी नहीं करती, फिर भी सब कुछ पूरा हो जाता है। - लाओ त्सू",
"quote_49" to "जिसके पास जमीन है उसके पास सोना है। - अफ्रीकी कहावत",
"quote_50" to "जमीन की देखभाल करें और जमीन आपकी देखभाल करेगी। - अज्ञात",
"quote_51" to "लघु स्तर के किसान हमारी खाद्य प्रणाली के नायक हैं। - अज्ञात",
"quote_52" to "दृढ़ता उत्कृष्टता की जुड़वां बहन है। एक गुणवत्ता की बात है; दूसरी, समय की। - माराबेल मॉर्गन",
"quote_53" to "कड़ी मेहनत सफलता का सूत्र है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_54" to "किसान का पसीना फसलों के लिए बारिश है। - अज्ञात",
"quote_55" to "आप किसी चीज़ के लिए जितनी कड़ी मेहनत करेंगे, उसे हासिल करने पर आप उतना ही बेहतर महसूस करेंगे। - अज्ञात",
"quote_56" to "सफलता छोटे-छोटे प्रयासों का योग है, जो दिन-रात दोहराए जाते हैं। - रॉबर्ट कोलियर",
"quote_57" to "बड़ा सपना देखें, कड़ी मेहनत करें, केंद्रित रहें। - अज्ञात",
"quote_58" to "चुनौतियां ही जीवन को दिलचस्प बनाती हैं और उन पर विजय पाना ही जीवन को अर्थपूर्ण बनाता है। - जोशुआ जे. मरीन",
"quote_59" to "अवसर का इंतजार न करें। इसे बनाएं। - अज्ञात",
"quote_60" to "आगे बढ़ने का रहस्य शुरुआत करना है। - मार्क ट्वेन",
"quote_61" to "गुणवत्ता कोई कार्य नहीं, बल्कि एक आदत है। - अरस्तू",
"quote_62" to "मुझे लगता है कि मैं जितना कठिन काम करता हूँ, उतना ही अधिक भाग्य मेरा साथ देता है। - थॉमस जेफरसन",
"quote_63" to "शक्ति और विकास केवल निरंतर प्रयास और संघर्ष के माध्यम से ही आते हैं। - नेपोलियन हिल",
"quote_64" to "साहस आगे बढ़ने की शक्ति होना नहीं है; यह तब आगे बढ़ना है जब आपके पास शक्ति न हो। - थियोडोर रूजवेल्ट",
"quote_65" to "सफलता की सड़क हमेशा निर्माणाधीन रहती है। - लिली टอมलिन",
"quote_66" to "असफलता वह मसाला है जो सफलता को उसका स्वाद देता है। - ट्रूमैन कैपोटे",
"quote_67" to "अपनी असफलताओं से शर्मिंदा न हों, उनसे सीखें और फिर से शुरू करें। - रिचर्ड ब्रैनसन",
"quote_68" to "कठिन समय नायक नहीं बनाता। यह कठिन समय के दौरान ही होता है जब हमारे भीतर का 'नायक' प्रकट होता है। - बॉब राइली",
"quote_69" to "चरित्र उस उत्साह के बीत जाने के बहुत बाद भी एक अच्छे संकल्प को निभाने की क्षमता है। - कैवेट रॉबर्ट",
"quote_70" to "यदि आप हार नहीं मानते हैं तो आपकी फसल जरूर आएगी। - अज्ञात"
